# HITANSH BHATT

hitbhatt007@gmail.com

Hitansh Bhatt
Personal Website

Github

Grade 12 student at Unionville High School. Passionate and interested in concepts related to programming and aviation. I look forward to expand my knowledge and skillset by learning from new experiences and by meeting and working with new people. Always willing to learn and grow. Enjoy learning programming and aviation concepts. Currently learning Python, web development and game development.

### **Skills**

- Leadership
- Analytical/Critical Thinking
- Communication

- Teamwork
- Time Management
- Resiliency

- Adaptability
- Self-Learning

# **Education**

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

#### Unionville High School, Markham, Ontario, Canada

• >95% average in high school STEM courses

MAY 2006 - MARCH 2018

PSBB Learning Leadership Academy, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

# **Experience**

FEBRUARY 2021

#### Mentor/ MLH NSBEHacks UofT

- Mentored a 24-hour hackathon of about 300 people, organized by Major League Hacking (MLH) and NSBEHacks – University of Toronto
- Helped participants with technical projects, idea formation, team formation, pitches and technical issues regarding code, Discord and Gathertown
- Helped with back-end and front-end open source projects.

OCTOBER 2020 - PRESENT

#### Moderator/Computer Science Club, Unionville High School

- Responsible for making sure all members comply with school policies
- Helping members with software installation issues and general programming queries regarding C# and Java

OCTOBER 2020 - PRESENT

#### Moderator/Math Club, Unionville High School

• Responsible for making sure all members comply with school policies

• Provide help with competitive and general math problems

#### OCTOBER 2020 - PRESENT

### Programming Team Member/Robotics Club, Unionville High School

• Currently learning to program robots built by the Mechanical and Electrical teams

#### OCTOBER 2020 - PRESENT

#### Member/Science Club, Unionville High School

• Currently learning about school-level and advanced science (Physics, Chemistry and Biology) concepts

#### JULY 2020 - PRESENT

#### Editor and Channel Manager/Apna Ghar Apna Swaad

- Responsible for managing channel logistics
- Edit videos
- Responsible for making sure that content complies with YouTube's policies

#### SEPTEMBER 2018 – JUNE 2020

#### Vice-Captain/Varsity Boys Soccer Team, Unionville High School

- Involvement in team strategizing such as positions, formations, etc.
- Leading the team in matches and practice
- Organizing drills

#### MARCH 2019 - OCTOBER 2019

#### Player/FCBEscola Toronto

• Represented FC Barcelona Academy Toronto

# **Volunteer Experience**

JANUARY 2021 – PRESENT

#### Team Lead/ Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh Shakha

• Currently leading a team of 6 yoga practitioners in an online Surya Namaskar Yogathon.

#### NOVEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2019

#### Front Desk Manager/Vishnu Mandir

- Data Entry
- On-phone communication
- Interacted with and helping senior citizens
- Managed donations
- Event coordination

# **Awards & Certifications**

2020

#### **Subject Award/Unionville High School**

• Grade 11 Computer Science subject award for achieving an overall average of 100%

#### 2019/2020

### Honour Roll/ Unionville High School

- "Given to students with an average of 80 or higher"
- Grade 11 Honour Roll (2020)
- Grade 10 Honour Roll (2019)

2017

### 3<sup>rd</sup> Place Clusters (South Zone)/ PSBB Learning Leadership Academy

• Award given for achieving the 3<sup>rd</sup> place position in a provincial handball tournament as a team

# **Activities**

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

### CS50's Introduction to Computer Science / Harvard University via edX

- Learning basics of programming languages such as C and Python
- Learning front-end development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Database management using SQL
  - Data Processing

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

### CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript/ Harvard University via edX

• Learning design and implementation of web apps with Python, JavaScript, and SQL using frameworks like Django, React, and Bootstrap

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

### Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python / MIT via edX

Learning concepts of programming using Python which provides a base for **Data Science** and **Machine Learning**

2019 - PRESENT

#### **Mathematics Contests / University of Waterloo**

- Fermat/2020
- Canadian Senior Mathematics Contest (CSMC)/2019
- Cayley/2019
- AMC 10/2019

# **Projects**

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

#### **Personal Website**

- Used HTML, CSS and JavaScript to build the website
- Statically deployed using Netlify
- Built with the purpose of providing a simple introduction, and more information about me such as skills and interests, as well as embedded links to my Github, LinkedIn, email and my resume.

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

#### **Checklist**

- A console-based Java program that provides checklists for commercial aircrafts
- Built with the purpose of easing aircraft checklist search

• Currently working on adding more adding more narrow-body and wide-body aircraft checklists

#### NOVEMBER 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

#### ICS4U

- A console-based representation of procedural tasks of a bank using Object Oriented Programming in Java
- Performs primary tasks such as adding/removing coins and displaying total
- Developed an algorithm to remove a specific value requested by the user (if available in their account). If the specific value is not available, the algorithm determines the most suitable value to be removed.

#### SEPTEMBER 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

#### **Code Breaker**

- A console-based game programmed in Java and developed on the concepts of the "Code Breaker" game.
- The game was divided into two components:
  - o Player vs AI (AI sets the code, player guesses)
  - o AI vs Player (Player sets the code, AI guesses)
- I coded the Player vs AI aspect of the game while my partner coded AI vs Player
- Developed an algorithm to provide clues to the user (black pegs and white pegs) in order to help them "break the code"
- Provided three stages of difficulties to the user: easy (10 guesses), medium (8 guesses), and difficult (6 guesses)

# **Tools & Technologies**

- Java, C#, C, Python
- Video Editing, YouTube
- Microsoft Office

HTML, CSS